tamuk.edu 2018-05-15

# Privacy Statement

## Texas A&M University-Kingsville respects your privacy.

The university's main website does not collect personal information about visitors.

We may collect certain information through the use of "cookies" or web beacons. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive at the request of a website. Among other things, cookies help us improve our Sites and your experience. Information obtained from cookies and linked to personally identifying information is treated as personal information. Anonymous identifiers are random strings of characters that are used for the same purposes as a cookie on platforms, including certain mobile devices, where cookie technology is not available. Web beacons are small, invisible graphic images that may be used on the Sites or in emails relating to the Sites to collect certain information about usage and effectiveness and monitor user activity on the Sites.

If you wish to block, erase, or be warned of cookies, please refer to your browser manufacturer’s information to learn about these functions.

## Web analytics

You can browse our website without giving us any personal information. We use web analytics technology, including specifically Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, to help us analyze traffic to the Sites in order to understand visitors’ interests and to continually update our Site to improve a user’s experience. Visit Google’s Privacy Policy to learn how Google Analytics collects and processes data. You may choose to engage Google Analytics’ currently available opt-outs for the web.

If you choose to enter a contest or giveaway, make a donation, fill out a form or subscribe to emails, you give the Foundation consent to monitor your browsing patterns in order to provide you with a better browsing experience for future visits and additional information on topics that you find of interest.

## Collection and use by third-party vendors

Third-party vendors, such as Google, may use cookies or other technologies to serve ads or deliver content on other websites based on your visits to our Sites and other sites on the Internet and to provide analytics services. These third parties may automatically collect information about your visits to this and other websites, your IP address, your ISP, the browser you use to visit our Site, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and conversion information. They do this using cookies, clear gifs or other technologies.

Information automatically collected by third parties may be used by third parties, among other things, to analyze and track data, to solicit donations, to deliver advertising or content on other websites based on your prior activities on this or other sites or targeted to your interests, and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Sites and the other sites tracked by these third parties. To manage settings for the Google advertising cookies and to opt-out of certain features, visit their Ad Settings.

This Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or clear gifs used by the third parties, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. If you would like to opt out of these cookies or obtain more information about this practice, visit Google Analytics opt-outs.

## Personal Information

Personal information that you provide via email or through other online means will be used only for purposes necessary to serve your needs, such as responding to an inquiry or other request for information. This may involve redirecting your inquiry or comment to another person or department better suited to meeting your needs.

We do, however, use server logs to collect information concerning your Internet connection and general information about your visit to our website. This information may be used to analyze trends; to create summary statistics for the purpose of determining technical design specifications; and to identify system performance or problem areas.

This means we sometimes acquire, record and analyze portions of the data that is entered into, stored on, and/or transmitted through this site by you. This information is only released -- when legally required -- to help law enforcement investigations, legal proceedings or internal investigations of A&M-Kingsville rule and regulation violations. These groups would use the information to track the electronic interactions back to the source computer(s) or account(s).

Some web pages at Texas A&M-Kingsville may collect personal information about visitors and use that information for purposes other than those stated above. Each web page that collects information will have a separate privacy statement that will tell you how that information is used.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your use of this website, please contact the webmaster or through regular mail at:

Texas A&M University-Kingsville

Office of Marketing and Communications

Attention: [marcomm@tamuk.edu](mailto:marcomm@tamuk.edu "email")

700 University Blvd. MSC 114

Kingsville, TX 78363-8202

SERVER LOG INFORMATION: The following information is collected from server logs for analysis

\- User/client hostname - The hostname (or IP address if DNS is disabled) of the user/client requesting access

HTTP header, "user agent" - The user-agent information includes the type of browser, its version, and the operating system it is running on

HTTP header, "referrer" - The referrer specifies the page from which the client accessed the current page

System date - The date and time of the user/client request

Full request - The exact request the user/client made Status - The status code the server returned to the user/client

Content length - The content length, in bytes, of the document sent to the user/client

Method - The request method used

Universal Resource Identifier (URI) - The location of a resource on the server

Query string of the URI - Anything after the question mark in a

URI Protocol - The transport protocol and version used
